（ルーク）大門カイト…　君に命じる。
Daimon Kaito, I order you.
ファイ・ブレインとなり　神のパズルを解け。
僕のために。
Achieve the Phi Brain and solve the Divine Puzzle.
For my sake.
（カイト）一体　何なんだよ…　ルーク！
What the hell was that about, Rook?
うっ。　何だ　お前ら？！
（銃撃音らしき音）
Who's there?!
あっ。
（ノノハ）退院決定おめでとう！　カイト！
Congratulations on your hospital release!
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
Blue Sun, Red Moon
というわけで　カイト退院決定記念
しりとり大会を開催しま～す！
So to commemorate Kaito's impending release from the hospital,
let's have a word chain tournament!
（ギャモン）けっ！　何で　そうなんだよ。
うっ！　ぐぐぐ。
Why that?
カイトに　少しでも　つらいこと
忘れてもらうの。
It's our job to make him forget about his troubles, even if just for a moment.
それが　私たちの役目。
わ　分かった。
I-I get it! But if you don't stop, I'll be in trouble!
このままじゃ　俺の方がつらい！
Okay then, I'll start with...
ハーイ！　じゃあ　私から　いくよ。
しりとりの「り」！
the "n" from "word chain"! Nelson Suplex!
リバース・スープレックス！
じゃあ　次　ギャモン君！
す　好きにしろ。
Next, Gammon!
X-whatever.
はい　キューちゃん　「ろ」だよ。　ろ！
（キュービック）あぁ！　ろ…。
Next up, Cubie! With an "r"!
An "r"...?
ろくでなし。
あれ～？！
どうしちゃったのかな　キューちゃん。
Rascal...
What's wrong with you, Cubie?
じゃあ　アナ！　「し」！
シニャックのル・ポン・デ・ザール。
Next, Ana, with an "l"!
Luce's Morning, Interior.
ハハハハッ。　何？　それ。　ええと
では　本日の主役のカイト君。　「る」！
What the heck is that?
And now today's star, Kaito, with an "r"!
ル…　ルーク…。
"r"? Rook...
あぁ　私の番か！
クッ　クレイジー　サイクローン！
Ah, now it's my turn with "k"!
Kesagiri chop!
あれ？　終わっちゃった～！
てへっ。
Whoops, it's over.
じゃ　じゃあ　次は　キューちゃんの
おもしろ発明コーナー！
Next, Cubie's Amazing Inventions Corner!
ええっ？！
ほら　何か出しなさいよ。
Come on, show us something!
いじめっ子　やっつける道具とか
０点取らないようにする道具とか→
Some tool that catches bullies or a pen that won't let you fail a test...
カイトが待ってるよ！
カイト…。
Kaito's waiting!
Kaito...
回想
（フンガ）そういう　たぐいまれなる
能力を持ったお方こそが→
Do you not think that a person of such amazing talent is more worthy to be at Daimon Kaito's side?
大門カイトと共に居るにふさわしいと
思いませんか？　ねぇ　天才君。
Right, little genius?
僕にできることなんて
何もないよ。
I can't do anything.
うっ…　キューちゃん。
Cubie...
What's wrong, Cubic? Did the big, bad POG boys bully you?
おい　キュービック
てめえ　どうしたんだ？
ＰＯＧに　いじめられでも
したのか？
Wait, seriously?
おい　まさか…。
何か　されたのか？！　ルークに！
Did Rook do something to you?
ううん　何でもないんだ。
本当に何でもないんだよ…　カイト。
No, nothing.
Nothing at all, Kaito.
あの思い出は　一体
何だったんだよ！
What are these memories then?
えっ！
カイト　どこ行くの？
Kaito, where are you going?
ルークを　ぶちのめしてやる。
絶対に許せねえ！
I'm gonna beat Rook to a pulp.
He's not getting away with this!
あぁ　待って！　カイト！
Wait, Kaito!
僕のせいだ。
It's my fault...
とんでもねえやつだなぁ…
ルークってのは…。
That Rook guy is twisted as hell.
カイトを　あんなふうに
しちまうなんてよ。
How could he mess Kaito up like that?
アナが思うに　カイトは蒼い太陽
あの子は緋い月。
I think... he's the red moon, while Kaito's the blue sun.
でも　不思議。
But it's weird.
２つの星は遠すぎるのに
どうして巡り会えたのかな？
If the sun and the moon are so far away, then how can they meet?
ここだ。
This is it.
I'm definitely going to find him.
心の声
あいつ　絶対　見つけ出してやる！
ちょ　ちょっと　カイト！
やめようよ。　怒られるよ。
Stop, Kaito! Don't do this, we'll get in trouble!
教室…？　じゃないよね。
何かの研究所？
This doesn't look like a classroom. More like a laboratory, maybe?
まるで　牢屋みたいね。
何で　こんな所に？
This looks like a prison. But why?
ねえ　カイト　ここって何なの？
Kaito, what is this place?
ねえ　カイト！
あっ？！
Kaito!
ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド！
Rook Banjo Crossfield!
ルーク君？
Rook...?
パズル…　これを解かねえと
中には入れねえってか。
A puzzle. I have to solve this to open the door?
居るのか？！　ルーク！
Are you here, Rook?!
何？　これ。
What... is this?
Children's clothes? But why?
子供の服？　どうして？
ルークの部屋だ。　１０年前
ルークは　ここに住んでたんだ。
This is Rook's room. He lived here ten years ago.
心の声
あいつ…　こんな所で…。
In a place like this...
これは？
何？！
What's this?
Find something?
ハハッ　いや…。
No...
カイト　もう帰ろう。
あの人　おかしいよ。
Kaito, shouldn't we go home?
That boy is really weird.
俺は　ジンを人質に取られてる。
He's holding Jin hostage. And it's Rook...
それに…→
ルーク…。
まだ　あったのか…。
It's still here?
あいつに最初会った夜も　ここから
遺跡へ冒険に出かけたんだ。
The night we first met, this is how we left to adventure in the ruins.
けど　そんな思い出も
全部ウソだったんだよな。
But all those moments were lies too.
カイト…。
Kaito...
He's been deceiving me since we were little.
あいつは　ガキの頃から
ずっと俺をだまして…。
I was a fool to believe his smile.
あの笑顔を信じた俺が
バカだったよ。
私　もしかしたら　まだ少しは
信じていたのかもしれない。
I think I might've still believed there was some hope left... for Rook.
ルーク君のこと。
でも　今日　身にしみて分かった。
彼は危険…。
But what I've seen today ensured me that he's dangerous.
カイトが　あの人に近づくのは
絶対によくないよ。
It's not good for Kaito to be close to him.
アナが思うに　思い出は
絶対に無くならない。
I think... memories never disappear.
うっ？
絵の具と同じ…。
Just like the paint I use.
どれだけ新しい色を混ぜても
昔の色は残るの　必ず…。
Even if I mix it with a new color, the old one still remains. Forever.
じゃあ　どうすれば…。
Then what can we...
このままじゃ　太陽は消えちゃう。
そうしたら　あの子の時間…。
If it goes on like this, the sun will disappear. Along with his life...
その前に…。
So before that...
回想
（ルーク）僕ね　今
新しい組木パズル　作ってるんだ。
You know, I'm making a new wooden puzzle now.
完成したら　カイトにあげる。
回想
えっ？！　ホント？！
I'll give it to you when it's done.
Really?
そしたら　その組木パズルと
回想
一緒に　いつも持ってて。
Then I want you to have it with you all the time, just like that one.
パズル見るたびに
回想
僕のこと　思い出してよ。
And then you can remember me whenever you look at it.
うん！　ありがとう　ルーク！
回想
Okay! Thanks, Rook!
あの約束は　何だったんだよ。
ウソつき野郎。
What did that promise mean then?
You liar.
Nonoha? What's wrong?
ノノハ　どうしたんだ？
こんな時間に。
What are you doing here so late?
ごめん。　起こしちゃった？
アナ　来てないよね。
Sorry, did I wake you up?
Ana's not here, right?
あっ？
居ないの…　ホテルに。
He's not at the hotel either.
居ないのって　こんな夜中に
どこ行くってんだ？
He's not? Where could he have gone in the middle of the night?
あっ？！　もしかして…。
What if...
どうした？
アナに話したの。
What is it?
I told him about the ruins where you went with Rook.
カイトとルーク君が行ったっていう
遺跡のこと。
聞こえる。
I can hear it.
（メイズ）ええ　はい。
すでに　パズルは改造しました。
Yes. Yes. I have already completed the puzzle.
ダ・ビンチも　そろそろ　招待状に
気づくころでしょう。
Da Vinci must have seen the invita—
グッド・イブニング～！
あぁ～！　お　お　お前は　ダ・ビンチ！
Good evening!
Y-Y-Y-You're Da Vinci?!
招待状を送ったばかりなのに
なぜ　もう　ここに？！
I just sent you the invitation, how are you already here?
（破る音）
勝手に　いいの？
アナ宛てなんでしょう　それ。
Are you sure about this? It's for Ana.
しかたねえだろう
居ねえんだから。
We've got no choice, he's not here.
あっ？！　何だ　こりゃ？
さあ…。
Huh? What's this?
Dunno...
絵の事は　分かんねえんだよなぁ。
絵というよりは　記号のような…。
These pictures are like Greek to me.
But this is more like a code...
（２人）パズル？！
A puzzle!
ぐっ　うっ　ぬぬぬっ　まあ　いいわ。
Well, whatever! That's one less problem!
これで　手間が省けたというもの。
ダ・ビンチの称号を持つあなたに
選択肢を　２つあげるわ！
Holder of the title of Da Vinci, I give you two choices.
一つは　大門カイトのそばから
離れるか→
First, you could get away from Daimon Kaito.
So big!
もう一つは　今夜
このグレートヘンジパズルで　命を落とすか。
Or second, you could die trying to solve this puzzle tonight.
I wonder how they built it.
Hey, listen to me when I'm talking!
…って　人の話を聞け！
えっ？！
ねえ　カイト　何なの？
そのグレートヘンジって？
Say, Kaito, what's that Greathenge?
ストーンヘンジって遺跡あるだろ？
You know Stonehenge, right?
あ～！　大きな石が
丸く並んでるやつよね。
That ancient circle of gigantic stones?
あれと同じストーンサークルだ。
It's a stone circle just like that.
ストーンヘンジは　夏至の太陽の位置を
想定して設計されている事から→
Stonehenge is oriented towards the sun at the summer solstice;
「古代の天文台」とも
言われてるんだ。
that's why they call it an ancient calendar.
けど　グレートヘンジは
何のために造られたのか→
But I had no idea what the purpose of Greathenge was.
さっぱり分かっていなかった。
ふ～ん。
だけど　ある日　ジンが
俺たちに教えてくれたんだ。
Then one day, Jin told us.
あれは　古代人が造った
巨大なパズルだって。
It's a gigantic puzzle built in ancient times.
俺とルークは　そのパズルを解くため
夜に学校を抜け出した。
I slipped out of school with Rook in the night to solve that puzzle.
それが　忘れらんねえ思い出に
なるとも　知らねえでな。
I might never be able to forget those memories.
呼んでる。
They're calling.
Oh, you shouldn't get close to it so carelessly.
（メイズ）おっと！　うかつに
近づかない方が　いいわよ。
The Greathenge is built to crush those who do.
このグレートヘンジは　近づいた人間を
押しつぶすように出来てるから。
ペシャンコ？
そうよ。　ペシャンコよ。
Into a pulp?
Yes, into a pulp!
正しいルートを通らないと
あんたみたいな　華奢な女の子→
If you deviate from the correct route, even a cute girl like you would be gone without a trace!
跡形もなく消えるわよ。
（アナ）あ～～！
フン　さすがに言葉もないようね。
I see you're at a loss for words.
アナ　男の子だけど。
え～っ？！　男の子？！
I'm a boy, by the way.
What?! A boy?!
お　男の子でも　跡形もなく
消えるわよ！　そうよ！
Boys would be gone without a trace as well! Boys too!
Yeah, that has nothing to do with it!
何の関係もないじゃない！
男だからって何だってのよ？！　ハッ？！
It's no different for boys!
と　とにかく　ルールを説明するわよ！
A-Anyway, let me explain the rules.
このグレートヘンジの謎を解き
正しいルートを読み取って→
To solve the riddle of Greathenge, choose the correct path and make it to the goal alive.
生きて　ゴールまで
たどりつきなさい。
ヒントは…　あ　あっ！
And for a hint...
そっか。
カイトの所に行きたいんだね。
I see... You want to see Kaito.
あぁ？！
アナ・グラム　１６歳　行きま～す！
Ana Gram, age 16, moving out!
えっ？！　ちょっ　ちょっと
まだヒント　言ってないんだけど！
Hey, wait! I haven't told you the hint yet!
It's fine, it's fine.
大丈夫　大丈夫。
あ～！　もう！　こんな子　居るわ！
私の一番苦手なタイプ。
Why do you have to be the type I can't stand?!
いい？　月のマークがある方だけ
通りなさいよ。
Listen. Only go between the moons.
太陽のマークの前を通ったら
岩が倒れるんだからね！
If you cross between suns, the stones will fall.
制限時間だって　あるんだから！
And there's a time limit as well!
５分！　５分過ぎたら
すべての岩が倒れるわよ！
Five minutes! After five minutes, all the stones will fall!
ねえ　聞いてる？！
Are you listening at all?
エッ。
ハァハァ…　これが　グレートヘンジ…。
That's the Greathenge?
あっ　アナ。
何やってんだ！
Ah, Ana!
What is he doing?!
（メイズ）待ちなさい。
やはり来たわね　大門カイト。
Stop right there!
I knew you'd come, Daimon Kaito.
でも　もうパズルは　始まってる。
But the puzzle has already begun.
今　パズルに　下手な手出しをすれば
すべての岩が倒れるわ。
If you try to tamper with the puzzle, all the stones will fall.
そしたら　あの子は　ペシャンコよ。
And he will be crushed to a pulp.
ＰＯＧか…
そんな　でまかせ　信じられっか！
The POG, huh? As if I'd believe what you say!
だったら　試してみたら？
うっ！
Then why not give it a try?
すべては　ルーク様の思いのままに…。
This is all according to Sir Rook's plan.
ルーク…　そんなパズルじゃなかった…。
Rook? This puzzle was different.
１０年前　俺とルークで来たときは→
When we came here together ten years ago,
そんな　おぞましい
パズルじゃなかったんだ。
カイト…。
it wasn't a horrifying puzzle like that!
Kaito...
「あいつ　俺との思い出も
何とも思っちゃいねえんだ。→
The time we spent together means nothing to him.
このパズルが
本当のあいつの姿だ！」。
This puzzle shows his true self!
ああっ　あそこ！
アナ～！　戻ってこい！
Look!
Ana, come back!
≫アナ～！
あっ　カイト～！
Ana!
Ah, Kaito!
戻ってこないの！
岩が倒れるから！
Don't come back! The stones will fall!
あぁ～。　ちょっと　あんたたちね
余計な口出し　しないでくれる！
Would you stop stupidly interfering?
危ないでしょう！
It's dangerous!
アナが思うに
何にも心配いらな～い！
I think... there's no need to worry!
アナ…？
Ana?
The answer was obvious right away.
だって　答えは
最初から見えてるもん！
ストーンヘンジが太陽ならば
このグレートヘンジは月！
If Stonehenge is the sun,
then the Greathenge is the moon!
何ですって？！
What?!
グレートヘンジは月。　そうか！
The Greathenge is the moon?
You're right! The stones aren't in a circle.
石は　サークルじゃない。　実は
月の形に並んでいるってことか。
They're ordered in the shape of the crescent moon.
そして　月のマークが指し示す道を
行けば…。
So if he follows the path marked by the moon...
本当に見えているというの。
あの子の目には…。
Can he really see it just like that?
はっ。　アナが思うに
パズルタイムは　これでおしまい。
I think... puzzle time is over now.
そんな…。
マジで解いちまった…。
That's...
He really solved it.
Hey!
≫（ギャモン）お～い！
大丈夫か？！
ギャモン君　キューちゃん！
You guys all right?
Gammon... Cubie?
あ～　あ～　待たせたな！
Sorry for the wait!
慣れねえ絵のパズルなんてやってたら
時間が　かかっちまった。
I'm not used to picture puzzles so it took a while!
これが　その答え！
２つの図柄を重ねて　すかせば→
The answer is simple! If you fold it into two,
グレートヘンジの文字になるんだ。
the overlapping parts read "GREATHENGE"!
俺に解けねえパズルは　ねえ！
There is no puzzle I can't solve!
パズルタイムの始まりだ！
いやいや　いやいや。
It's puzzle time!
Not really...
あっ　アナが…。
Oh, Ana!
オカベ君！　アナを救うんだ！
Okabe! We have to save Ana!
おい　やめろ！
（キュービック）行け～！　オカベ君！
Hey, stop!
Go, Okabe!
（潰される音）
（２人）あ～？！
アナ～！
Ana!
わ　私のグレートヘンジが…。
My Greathenge...
うっ　アナは？！　アナ～！
Is Ana...? Ana!
（キュービック）あっ！　アナだ！
It's Ana!
うん！
よかった！
Thank goodness...
（ギャモン）あぁ？！　何だ？　この形。
Why is it shaped like that?
（キュービック）これは　三日月？
It's a crescent moon?
これが　月のストーンヘンジの正体。
This is the moon version of Stonehenge.
アナには　最初から
この形が見えていたのね。
Ana could see its shape from the beginning.
君が　アナを呼んだんだね。
You called me, right?
Ana, why did you come here all alone?
アナ　どうして　１人で
こんな場所に来たんだ？
はい！
（２人）あっ！
Here.
声がしたの。　この子　ずっと
カイトに会いたがってたんだよ。
I heard its voice.
It wanted to meet you all along.
あっ？！　「カイトへ　ルークより」。
"To Kaito. From Rook."
（ルーク）僕ね　今
回想
新しい組木パズル　作ってるんだ。
You know, I'm making a new wooden puzzle now.
回想
完成したら　カイトにあげる。
I'll give it to you once it's done.
ルークの作ったパズル…。
The puzzle Rook was making...
あのパズル　完成してたのか。
He finished it?
Ah, we couldn't solve it.
あ～！　解けなかった。
回想
（ルーク）難しすぎるよ　このパズル。
This puzzle is just too hard.
ねえ　カイト。
ん？
回想
これから毎日　ここに来ようよ。
Hey, Kaito! Let's come here every day!
大人になるまでに
回想
絶対　解こう！　このパズル！
Let's solve this puzzle before we grow up!
回想
うん　そうしよう！　毎日来よう！
Okay! Let's come here every day.
Oh, right, Kaito.
そうだ　カイト。　この前
回想
話した僕のパズルなんだけど…。
About the puzzle I told you about.
回想
（２人）ん。
（所長）いけませんね　ルーク様。
You shouldn't be here, Sir Rook.
無断外出は
回想
禁じられているはずです。
You're forbidden to leave without permission.
あっ　はい。
回想
Y-Yes...
You, go on home already.
回想
さあ　君はもう　帰りなさい。
カイト　行くんだ。
回想
Kaito, go.
ルーク！　あしたも一緒に
パズル解こうな～！
Rook! Let's solve puzzles together tomorrow as well!
それが　ルークを見た最後だった。
That was the last time I saw him.
あったかい！
So warm. This warmness is him from back then.
この　あったかい感じは
あの時のルークだ。
アナが思うに　あの子はウソなんか
ついてなかったんだよ。
I think... he wasn't lying to you.
１０年前のあの子は　本当に
カイトのことが好きだった。
He really liked you ten years ago.
ありがとう…　アナ。
Thanks, Ana.
あのパズル…
ずっと　無くしたと思ってた。
That puzzle... I thought I lost it.
（ルーク）やだ～！
回想
ううっ　うわっ！
I don't wanna!
回想
離せ！　離せ！
Let go! Let go!
回想
やだ～！　あそこには
もう　戻りたくな～い！
No! I don't wanna go back there!
（所長）やれやれ　そんな
回想
感情まで学んでしまったとは…。
Oh, my. To think you've learned such emotions...
回想
プログラムの再構成が必要ですね。
We must restructure the program.
うっ！　カイト…。
回想
Kaito...
あんな所にあったんだ…。
So it was there...
（ビショップ）ルーク様…。
Sir Rook?
ほら　太陽が　もう一度。
Look, the sun is back.
ルーク…。
Rook...
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.